[
    {
      "question": "Which among the following has highest velocity?",
      "options": ["Hurricane", "Tornado", "Typhoon", "Cyclone"],
      "answer": "Tornado"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which of the following situations the force applied by the weight of a person becomes zero in a lift?",
      "options": [
        "Lift moves up with an acceleration of 9.8 meter per sq. second",
        "Lift moves down with an acceleration of 9.8 meter per sq. second",
        "Lift moves up with an speed of 9.8 meter per second",
        "Lift moves up with down speed of 9.8 meter per second"
      ],
      "answer": "Lift moves down with an acceleration of 9.8 meter per sq. second"
    },
    {
      "question": "If the distance between the earth and the sun becomes one-fourth of what it is now, the gravitational force exerted on the earth by the sun would be:",
      "options": [
        "One-fourth of what it is now",
        "One-sixteenth of what it is now",
        "Sixteen times of what it is now",
        "Four times of what it is now"
      ],
      "answer": "Sixteen times of what it is now"
    },
    {
      "question": "Two pieces of ice at 0°C would freeze together if pressed against each other and then released. In this context, which among the following is the correct principle in action in this?",
      "options": [
        "The melting point of pure ice decreases with pressure.",
        "The melting point of pure ice increases with Pressure",
        "The melting point of pure ice first increases, then decreases with pressure",
        "The melting point of pure ice first decreases then increases with pressure"
      ],
      "answer": "The melting point of pure ice decreases with pressure."
    },
    {
      "question": "Due to which of the following phenomena, the coloured glass appears white when crushed into fine powder?",
      "options": ["Total Internal Reflection", "Diffraction", "Scattering", "Refraction"],
      "answer": "Scattering"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the value of Triple point of water?",
      "options": ["273.16 K", "273.16° C", "0° C", "-273.16 K"],
      "answer": "273.16 K"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the work done by centripetal force in case of Uniform Circular Motion?",
      "options": ["1 joule", "0 joule", "Depends on the magnitude of Force", "None of the above"],
      "answer": "0 joule"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is/are independent of mass during the projectile motion?",
      "options": ["Time of Flight", "Horizontal Range", "Maximum Height", "All of the above"],
      "answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
      "question": "The work done by a variable force is given by:",
      "options": [
        "area under the force curve and the displacement axis",
        "square of the area under the force curve and the displacement axis",
        "natural log of the area under the force curve and the displacement axis",
        "twice the area under the force curve and the displacement axis"
      ],
      "answer": "area under the force curve and the displacement axis"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is correct about the value of acceleration due to gravity?",
      "options": [
        "it is greater at mountains than in plains",
        "it is lesser at mountains than in plains",
        "it is equal for mountains and plains",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "it is lesser at mountains than in plains"
    }
  ]
  